# CHIDOZIE VICTOR NNACHOR

Amsterdam, Netherlands Phone: +31684798391

Email: odogwu.naija@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="http://www.odogwudozilla.com">www.linkedin.com/in/chidoziennachor</a>
Portfolio Page: <a href="http://www.odogwudozilla.com">http://www.odogwudozilla.com</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Odogwudozilla">https://github.com/Odogwudozilla</a>

#### **SUMMARY:**

I am a fledgling software developer with a keen interest in building up a career in the software industry. I currently hold a **Software Engineer** role at <u>Keylane</u>, a leading SaaS platform provider supporting all core processes of insurers and pension providers across the Benelux, DACH and the Nordics. Before a career move to IT, I worked in the financial industry (banking). I have a Bachelors in Economics and an MSc in Information Technology. I am interested in work environments that promote symbiotic collaboration, using technology to both predict and change behaviour positively, and building efficient data systems. I am open to opportunities that offer persistent challenges to the intellect and skill-set.

#### **SKILLS OVERVIEW:**

#### Technical Skills:

- Java, Ruby;
- Front-end (HTML5, JavaScript);
- Database (SQL, MySQL, Postgresql);

## Frameworks/Tools:

- Linux, Git, Gradle;
- Rails, MVC, Heroku, AWS;

## Project Management Skills:

- Agile Software Development (Scrum);
- Test-Driven Development (TDD)
- CI-CD;

#### Soft Skills:

- Communication, Teamwork
- Leadership, Self-Oriented

#### **EDUCATION:**

## MSc, Information Technology, University of Aberdeen

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

Modules include: Web Application Development; Human Computer Interaction; Enterprise Computing and Business; Fundamentals of Software Project Management; Systems Analysis & Design; Information Security; Database Systems and Big Data.

## BSc, Economics (2:1), University of Nigeria, Nsukka, Nigeria

Sept 2006 - Nov 2010

Modules Include: Economic Theory (Micro/Macro), History of Economic Thought, Monetary and Financial Economics, Philosophy and Logic, Mathematical Economics, Research Methods in Economics, Operations Research, Demography and Population Economics, Economics of Planning, Advanced Statistics and Econometrics, etc.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## Software Engineer, Keylane B.V., Utrecht, Netherlands

Sept 2019 - Present

- Implementing Customer requirements through 'Requests For Change' (RFCs).
- Technical analysis, Proofs of concept, Code Reviews.
- Testing: TDD and Regression testing.
- Bugs-fixing.
- Product/features Demos.

## Software Developer, Scotland's Rural College, Aberdeen, UK

May 2018 - Aug 2018

• Designed and Implemented the pilot phase of the web application at <u>SRUC field trials</u>, a greenfield project;

## Head, Cash Operations & Customer Front Desk, First Bank, Nkpor, Nigeria Sep 2015 - Aug 2016

- Branch Vault Management and Setting of local performance metrics;
- Process Troubleshooting, Cash Evacuation and maintenance of ATMs for 100 percent uptime;
- Fortnightly in-branch training of staff on new or revamped products and services, and new regulatory directives by the regulatory bodies.
- Customer relationship management with 10 minutes TAT and 90% complaints resolution on a daily basis;
- Coordinate feedback between Services and Retail Departments.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE:**

## Training/Learning Anchors, Keylane, Utrecht

Apr 2020 - Date

I have anchored a couple of internal efforts at training others in a new skill or interesting technical subject (e.g. Design Patterns) at my current workplace as part of internal Learning and Development projects.

## Career Ambassador Programme, Aberdeen University

Sept 2018 - Mar 2019

Student representative for the Career Department of the university who have a broad range of duties including: participation at careers events which provides opportunities to disseminate information about University ancillary services to students; attending monthly training workshops; conducting case studies and interviews and generally selling the university brand.

## Cantcha (CodeTheCity, Aberdeen)

May 2018

A project organised by Code The City Aberdeen themed "<u>Hacking Our Relationship With Alcohol</u>". The aim of this project is to demonstrate how difficult it is to tell an alcoholic drink label from a non-alcoholic one by the ordinary user, and using machine learning to develop a captcha that can catch these grey areas.

## **English Language Support Project, Aberdeen University**

Feb - March 2018

Mentoring current international offer holders vis-à-vis providing them with insight on the student life experience to nudge them in the right direction preparatory to eventual sojourn in the University as well as helping them practise their English for those who may need a little help in that direction.

# **Peer Education Trainer**

Aug 2011 - June 2012

HIV/AIDs Peer Education Training Project through the NYSC, Sayonti, Lau LGA, Nigeria Organised and successfully implemented an HIV/AIDS Peer Education Training of the students of GDSS, Sayonti, Taraba State; Organised Road shows and sensitisation seminars in the community; Partnered with the Local Hospital to sensitize pregnant women and other vulnerable people on health issues and personal hygiene.

## President, Students Association

April, 2009 - April, 2010

National Economics Students Association (NESA), UNN Chapter, Nigeria Supervised administrative duties of the organization; Organized and coordinated Excursions, talk shows, debates, seminars and symposia both within and outside the department of Economics.

## **SOFT-SKILLS DETAILS:**

*IT*: I am continually improving my skillset, especially in Object Oriented Programming and Frontend development. I work in a self-organising Dev-ops team using the agile framework. I have varied skills required of the modern day programmer (using the academic process as a valuable guide) and will keep on improving on those. I also have hands-on experience in Hardware troubleshooting and repairs.

**Communication:** I have successfully completed curated courses/trainings on business communication at every job I have had. I have also been in positions in which I have to make sell ideas to varied audiences which have helped hone my communication skills.

**Leadership:** I understand the varied nuances to managing human capital and other resources to optimally achieve stated goals. I have learned how to leverage on the platform for policy formulation and implementation offered by leadership positions to galvanise effort towards achieving objectives. Although no pronounced leadership hierarchy is expected in an agile environment, it is also often true that someone will have to bell the cat.

**Teamwork:** As a student and as department president, much of the academic and non-academic tasks requires teamwork and the collaboration of everyone on board. My current job requires substantial amount of team work in a scrum/Agile framework and has ingrained in me the indispensability of cooperation in the professional settings. At the core of my current efforts, therefore, is the effective use of collaboration to complete projects.

## **AWARDS:**

Recipient: Nigeria Liquefied Natural Gas (NLNG) Postgraduate Scholarship (2018)